Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records 5556
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records
1926-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
5556
6 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Arbitration awards, meeting minutes, and correspondence of the Switchmen's Union of North America.
5664257
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 25, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Switchmen's Union of North America is among the older of the railway brotherhoods. Beginning in 1877 with the formation of a local Switchmen's organization in Chicago, the movement became national when the Switchmen's Mutual Aid Association of North America held its first meeting nine years later.
This association was destroyed, as a result of a disastrous lockout by the Chicago Northwestern and the 1888 strike against the Chicago, Burlington and Quincy which had equally unfortunate results. Building on what was left of the S.M.A.A., several lodges met in Kansas City in October of 1854 and formed the Switchmen's Union of North America.
By the time of its merger into the United Transportation Union in 1969, the single Chicago labor organization of 1877 had grown to international status with 275 lodges in the United States and Canada having a combined membership of 12,000.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5034: Switchmen's Union of North America Records 5034 MB: Switchmen's Union of North America Memorabilia 5034 P: Switchmen's Union of North America Photographs 5084: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records 5405 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Constitutions on Microfilm 5406 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Arbitration on Microfilm 5447: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Unification Minutes and Convention Proceedings 5556 AV: Switchmen's Union of North America Audio-Visual Materials 5590: Switchmen's Union of North America Lake Shore Lodge 55 Membership Registers 5613: Switchmen's Union of North America Oakland Lodge 158 Meeting Minutes 5630: W.B. Meyers Papers
Railroads -- United States.; Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Switchmen's Union of North America
5664257
- NRAB, 1st Division Award Files, c. 1950's, 1960's. (Box 1)
  - Award 17258 Docket 30338 DLW, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dockets Ex Parte Submissions Southern Pacific Company, 1952-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dockets No. Claims Kearney, Smith, Jennings et al., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Docket 30375(51-565) Ed Jennings, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Awards and Dockets, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dockets, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dockets and Awards, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dockets, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dockets 4 Cases; Foreman Allonge, Hanson McCoy and Jordan, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Docket 30-328 - Bfo, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 30463 denied, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Docket No. 51567 Award No. 17525 Southern Pac. Co., 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Joint Submission CRI&P A.A. Bloddy, A.E. Sherwood etc. Docket #31351, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Docket 31372 Claim of Committee against using foreman to perform pilot service, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Award No. 17387 No. 17388 Dockets 31-255; 31-256, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - M-1131 31390 Docket - 17392, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Docket No. 31400 Award No. 17511, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - SP Docket No.31538 Award No. 17683, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Award - 16747 Nesci D-1173, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Award - 17903 31595, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Docket No. 31697 Award No. 17684, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - So. Pac. Co. Claim of H.M. Mayberry, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Award No. 17522 Docket No., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Docket - 31-675 Award 16784, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - SoPac. Dockets and Awards, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Buffalo Creek Claim of M. Tabor, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Claim of Switchman R. J. Clemmons, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Southern Pacific Claim of Switchman Fields, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Docket No. 31819 Award No. 17789, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Southern Pacific, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - S.P. 1622 Docket 31869 Award 16911, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - SoP. S> 1618 Foreman Dull, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Claim of M.D. McFerrin & E.R. Faust, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - S.P. Claim of Jones, Norvelt and Sullivan, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - S.P. Claim of Oscar S. Simmons S-1705, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Buffalo Creek Claim of 4man Taber, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - LST&T One Days Pay For Switchman, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - S.P., 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - SP Claim of Switchman J. Drummond Jr., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - S.P. Claim of Wiltise, Emerson et al S. 1707, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Claim for V.L. Bird, Bakersfield Yard Case No. S. 1676, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - S.P. Claim of Martinsen, Pfau S. 1695, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - S.P. Claim of K.F. Smith, et al. S-1698, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - SP G.R. Sollars, Eugene, Oregon, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - S.P. Claim of K.W. Leonhart Port Costa, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - S.P. Claim Miguel F.E. Carr S. 1725, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - S.P. Claim Bakersfield, Calif., 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - S.P. Claim C.T. Mathews S. 1725, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - S.P. S-1754 Docket 32678 Award, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - S.P. 1746 Claim for Senior, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - S.P. Claim 1 day for 3 senior extra men, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Claim for Foreman S.R. Watson, Helpers, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - S.P. Claim L.C. Wray, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Docket 32809 Award SP, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Claim of T.L. Larned, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - S.P. Claim of D.D. Wiltz, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - SP Docket No. 32832 Award No. 18275, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Claim of W.J. Rumbaugh, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Claim for 3 Switchmen, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - SP Dockett 32844 Award 18316 denied, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Docket 32972 Award 18503, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Docket No. 32-989 Award No. 18505, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Claim S-1775, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- NRAB, 1st Division Award Files, c. 1950's, 1960's. (Box 2)
  - D.R. Cummins, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Joint Submission CRI&P, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Indianapolis Union Railway, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Carrier's File SUNA File Claim of C.C. Gray E.F. Kotreas, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - SUNA Carrier, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - SUNA Carrier, 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - SUNA Carrier, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Claim G. Pitzmeyer, 1949-1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Joint Submission CRI&P, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - SUNA Carrier, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Joint Submission-Great No. Claim of 4man Gordon and Helpers Bieber and Keenen, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Great Northern Ry. Claim, 1949-1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Claim for E.J. Elkins, 1948-1957 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Indpls. Union Ry. E.J. Thale Case, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - J.F. Manson suspension from M&St.L., 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Joint Submission Claim for 8 Hours Geo Koemitz, Foreman Halners English Rudiger, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Indianapolis Union Railway Claim of 4man D. Maxwell, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Indpls. Union Ry. - C.D. Weed et al., 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Great Northern-Joint submission Claim for Geo. Hastin and E.L. Riebe, 1948-1954 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Claim of L.E. Crady SoPac., 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Southern Pacific W.F. Baker, Roseville, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Buffalo Creek. Claim of Switchman M. Taber, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Indpls. Union Ry. D. Eggers, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Indpls. Union Ry. J.W. Moore, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Indpls. Union Ry. Helper Miskow Award No., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Claim of 4man J. Prouafet et al. Western Pacific, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Hermann Schmitt, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Docket Award, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Docket Award, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Docket Award, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Docket Award, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Docket No.16987-16986 16986 16984 16983, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Claim of Chas. Hutzler A.F. Johnson, 1951-1957 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Claim of W.R. Meyer, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Claim of switch crews working Dec. 27, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Claim L.J. Logan, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Award 17034 Docket 28633, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - L.J. Logan et al., 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Dockets 28693-18694 H. Francz R. Munger, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Awards 17035-17040-17041-17051-17094-95, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Claims of Engineer J.W. Long and J.F. Long, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Buffalo Creek in of Yard Foremen, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - RI Denied, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Claim day's pay IST&T 4man S.J. Gall and helpers Fisher and Mankoski, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - D-1107, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - DL&W--Scranton, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Joint Submission RI-SU Claim for yard dayat Amarillo, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Switchmen's Union of N.A. and Western Railroad Company, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - J.B. Gribble case, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - M&STL claim of E.R. Hanrahan, 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Foreman E. Flynn; Foreman W. Kozlowski, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Dismissal, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Awards Mochinal Stenko, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Indianapolis Union Ry. I-1056, 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Denied - 250, 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Dockets 29814 - 29815 - 29816 - 29817, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Claims denied, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Docket No. 29852, 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - DL&W vs. SUNA, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Joint Submission RI & SU re claim of Switchman F.L. Steinbeck, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - S.P.--Glen L. Foster, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Penn Central Merger, AFL-CIO Officers Salaries Chart. (Box 3)
  - Sal Committee - 1967, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newspapers; Misc. things, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - NYC - Pennsy - Merger, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1967 AFL-CIO Survey (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - ACL - SAL, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Penn Central Merger, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Chairman, Board of Directors, Clarence Ferguson's Records; Committee of General Managers, Reports 1909; International Vice President Report 1963; Receipt book (dues); December 1968 letter to Secretary-Treasurer; Agreement 1951 (union shop). (Box 4)
  - Silverstone magnetic Sound Recording Tape (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    2 reels
  - Erie-DLW (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Committee to Preserve Railroad Service, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - M.J. Knapik Union Shop Hearing Claim to Title of BRT Gen. Chairman Illegal Removal from Office, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - United Transportation Union, 1964-1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - United Transportation Union, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - United Transportation Union, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - United Transportation Union "Job Benefit Fund", 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - U.T.U. General Committees of Adjustments, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Case (File 14772-4) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - United Transportation Union, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Penn Central Accounting Division Philadelphia, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Misc., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Misc., 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Re: Supplementary Pensions 1966 Amendment To. Railroad Retirement Act 1937 and Taxing Act (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Minutes of the International Board of Directors Executive Session, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Misc., 1965 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - RE: Claim of Former Int'l. V. Pres. H.P. Watson for 1963 and 1964 Vacation Allowance, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Re: 64d&f - Constitution, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Attention Under Arb. Bd. 282, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Switchmen's Union, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Bd. Dir., 1962 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Western District and Public Utilities Commission of Ohio, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Report to 1959 Convention Board of Directors (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Folders, 1960-1968 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Switchmen's Union and BRT, 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Brief History of "Burial Fund" and Beneficiary Department" of the S.U. of N.A. By George Monroe, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Form 64&64F App. Rex. 12/64, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Fleete's Green Sheet Information, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Arbitration Award Foremen's Differential, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Genl. Comm. NYC Lines West, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Change of Date 1963 Convention (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Additional files. (Box 5)
  - Protest to Civil Service Comm. Railroad Retirement Bd., 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Chicago to Eastern Illinois Re: Employees Required, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Anglo-American, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - General File on: Labor, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Circular of Instructions, 1958-1961 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Employees of the Cleveland Union Terminals Company, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - NYCLW - 1926 Agreement, 1926-1946 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Switchmen's Union, 1927-1945 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - #299, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cleveland Lodge 55, 1932-1937 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Double Track - Switchtender - 1933, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Papers, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - C.U.T. Co. - B+O PSGR Trains - Aug. '34, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Letters, 1934-1941 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Local Working Agreements, 1930-1938 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Schedules, Rules, Booklets, 1910-1960 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - BRT and other Unions, 1919-1962 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Agreement June, 25. 1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Additional files. (Box 6)
  - Injunction - Judge Knight - Herald Reese, 1950-1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Vacation Disputes, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - C. U. T. Negotiations, 1930-1946 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dockets 2565 - Switchtenders - West End Old Depot, 1934-1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Docket No. 16442, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Daniel W. Collins, 1962-1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Letters and Merger, 1916-1963 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Cash R-690 I NYC times west., 1964 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1958 - Linndale Switchtenders (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Shuttle Dispute - Lodges 55-299, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - R-690 and R-1150 C. Ferguson, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Cut-a-2 Cut claim for S.H. CUT " WE Sw.T., 1934 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - R-690 Election System, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Switchmen's Union of North America, et al. v. National Mediation Board, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Pittsburgh + Lake Erie R.R., 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Switchmen's Union of North America, 1941-1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - UTU, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Vice President Expense Statements - #61, 1956-1964 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Officers Expense Statements, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Switchmen's Union of North America: A.F.L.-C.I.O., 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - New York Central Railroad Company - General Yardmaster's Office, 1930-1963 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Eligible Voter List - R-690, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - NYCLW - Gen. Chmn. Contests, 1933-1943 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Cleveland Union Terminal, Lodge 299 index inside, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - H.C.D. - S.U.N.A. 299, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Application of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen for New York Central System contract to Govern Yardmen on 15 railroads, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Application of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen for New York Central System contract to Govern Yardmen on 15 railroads, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Application of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen for New York Central System contract to Govern Yardmen on 15 railroads, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Application of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen for New York Central System contract to Govern Yardmen on 15 railroads, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Application of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen for New York Central System contract to Govern Yardmen on 15 railroads, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Application of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen for New York Central System contract to Govern Yardmen on 15 railroads, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 26)